John Gabunas

Programmer/Analyst - Lincoln Financial Group

West Hartford, CT - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/John-Gabunas/f53459bef4771abf

A Senior Programmer Analyst with a strong background in Vantage One application support, including UL, Variable products including Life and Annuity, Admin, IPS and DSS. experience also includes COBOL programming, and DB2 database administration; also 4 years experience with the INGENIUM insurance system, including use of Pathfinder.

CLIENT/SERVER: Databases Lotus Notes, SQL Windows

Languages COBOL/2, MicroFocus COBOL

Tools MS-Office, MS-Project, MicroFocus Workbench, Mainframe Express, Lotus 1-2-3

O/S, Network Windows NT/2000/XP, MS-DOS, OS/2, LAN

MAINFRAME: Databases DB2, SQL, QMF, VSAM

On-line CICS

Languages COBOL, COBOL II, Easytrieve Plus, Spufi

Tools Abend-Aid, Changeman, CA-7, CList, SQL, CompuSet, Documerge, Elixir, Endeavor, File-Aid, JCL,

JES, Panvalet, Syncsort, TSO/ISPF, Xpediter

O/S, Network OS/MVS, DOS/VSE

HARDWARE: IBM Mainframe, IBM PC and Compatibles

APPLICATIONS: Insurance Quality Assurance

Healthcare Manual Testing

Life & Annuities Integration Testing

Vantage Regression Testing

INGENIUM/Pathfinder Development and Enhancements

All levels of testing -

Integration, Regression,

System and Quality Assurance

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer/Analyst

Lincoln Financial Group - Hartford, CT - April 2013 to Present

at Lincoln Financial Group

Participation: Did much the same work as I did as a consultant in the previous consulting assignment with MODIS. Worked on Quality Assurance and BA testing; having level one responsibility to respond to and correct abends in test cycles and follow them to completion. JCL proficiency and modified several jobs in our cycles to run faster and more efficiently. Created end of cycle report to our surrounds, who use Fusion data in their systems, and with whom I worked closely in meeting their needs.

Hardware/Software:

COBOL, DB2.CICS, Fusion Vantage, DASD, PVCS, File Manager, Word, XCEL

Programmer/Analyst

MODIS Consulting - Hartford, CT - April 2012 to March 2013

at Lincoln Financial Group

Participation: Worked on Quality Assurance and BA testing; having level one responsibility to respond to and correct abends in test cycles and follow them to completion. JCL proficiency and modified several jobs in our cycles to run faster and more efficiently. Created end of cycle report to our surrounds, who use Fusion data in their systems

Hardware/Software:

COBOL, DB2.CICS, Fusion Vantage, DASD, PVCS, File Manager

Programmer/Analyst

Knight of Columbus - New Haven, CT - January 2007 to May 2011

Participation: Worked on enhancements and system modifications, and conversions to INGENIUM insurance application system. Assisted in building five test regions and played a key role in the entire testing process, from integration, regression, System and Quality Assurance testing phases; having level one responsibility to respond to and correct abends in test cycles and follow them to completion. Modified several online screens using Pathfinder. Worked on several bridge programs between our Life-70 system and the INGENIUM system. Also made modifications and enhancements to parts of the Fraternal system.

Hardware/Software:

Programmer/Analyst

Health Net Insurance - Shelton, CT - May 2006 to October 2006

Participation:

Participation: Composition Programmer - Created and modified customer documents for distribution.

Strong customer interaction; heavy testing; maintained and modified COBOL system.

Hardware/Software: Compuset, Cobol

Programmer/Analyst

Phoenix Insurance - Springfield, MA - February 2006 to May 2006

Participation: As a member of Outsource Team, performed production support and enhancements.

Involved, analysis, coding and testing.

Hardware/Software:

COBOL, DB2, CICS, Vantage-One, Endeavor, File-Aid, JCL

Programmer/Analyst

CSC - East Hartford, CT - September 2005 to February 2006

Participation: Worked on an upgrade/conversion project for a large New England insurance company using Vantage-One. Updated 60-70 modules. Updated some 30 Copybooks and 10-15 JCL members. Learned new mid-tier software product, Mainframe Express (MFE).

Hardware/Software:

COBOL, DB2, CICS, Vantage-One, JCL, Endeavor, File-Aid, Mainframe Express

Non-IT Employment - Westerly, RI - December 2002 to September 2005

Programmer/Analyst

CIGNA Corporation - East Hartford, CT - May 2002 to November 2002

Participation: Worked on the Billing System, provided production support and creating Excel spreadsheets and PowerPoint presentations for various levels of management. Also reviewed and updated Brio reports for distribution.

Hardware/Software: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Brio

Programmer/Analyst

CSC - November 2000 to September 2001

Participation: Worked on STP project - on the Product Wizard portion - converting Vantage VSAM table files into DB2 tables. Wrote 50-60 modules, including conversion modules and DB2 table handlers. Wrote cycle JCL and ran cycles through 3 phases of testing. Performed many DBA duties throughout the project. Created Spufis, ran DB2 utilities, and performed Binds. Managed tables in 12 databases. Performed integrated testing with all portions of Product Wizard - GUI frontend and Product Wizard DB2 interface to mainframe, as well as testing with OTA.

Hardware/Software:

Expeditor, File-Aid

Connecticut Mutual/MassMutual - April 1993 to October 2000

Position: Programmer/Analyst

Participation: Worked on the Product Engine Team during merger with MassMutual.

Responsibilities include IPS and DocuMerge support for the Product Engine as well as production

Support responsibilities on a rotating basis. Completed course in DocuMerge, as well as in-house

training in Endeavor, and several homegrown classes on the business we support and on the Vantage product in general. By establishing a working relationship with many peers in various

Technical positions such as output operation, security administration, the DASD team, CA- Dispatch, and Systems Integrity, was a critical part of our team. Also worked on New Product

Development Team. Heavily involved in Unit Testing and System Testing of new variable product,

including running full cycle tests. Gained experience with IPS and DSS leg of Vantage-One.

Extensive experience in production support issues, as it relates to Vantage-One, particularly on the Admin System. Have knowledge of Vantage-One UL products as well as Variable Products.

Worked on the upgrade of Vantage-One version 12.0 to Vantage 14.0; Involved in many database conversions

Hardware/Software:

COBOL, DB2. CICS, Vantage-One, DASD, CA-Dispatch, DocuMerge, Endeavor, File-Aid

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut

Diploma in Computer Operations

Computer Processing Institute